I am young economist with programming experience for quantitative research. My main areas of interest are Economics of Education, Labor Market and Urban Economics. Currently I work as a lecturer at the Adolfo Ibáñez University and as research assistant at the Center for Regional Economics and Policy (CEPR-UAI). I worked as a teacher assistant in graduate and undergraduate courses in fields of microeconomics and data science. I stand out for being determined, independent, and hardworking.

**CONTACT INFORMATION**  CL: (+56) 9 662 450 76

masielfeld@gmail.com; martin.sielfeld.o@edu.uai.cl

## **EDUCATION**

## Adolfo Ibáñez University

## Master of Science in Economics (ranked 1st out of 7 students)

I Sem. 2020 - I Sem. 2021 Thesis: "Consequences of the spatial heterogeneity of the school supply

- and parent's lack of information in a School Choice system".
- Grade: 7 (out of 7).
- Advisor: Esteban Lopez Ochoa (UTSA).
- Committee: Sebastian Gallegos (UAI), Luis Hersckovic (UAI).
- Document: link.

Bachelor degree in Economics Sciences (17th out of 58 students) I Sem. 2016 - II Sem. 2019 I Sem. 2017 - II Sem. 2018 Minor in Political Sciences

## German School of Santiago

Primary and Secondary Education

#### I Sem. 2004 - II Sem. 2015

## **CURRENT POSITIONS**

## Lecturer, Adolfo Ibáñez University

Main tasks: preparation and presentation of lecture's topics and programming-based labs in R for data science.

# Research assistant, Center for Regional Economics and Policy - UAI

- Main tasks: review literature; organize and participate in research meetings and seminars; create R scripts to clean, organize and merge datasets from public and private sources; run econometric models (OLS, IV, discrete choice, non-parametric, etc.), organize and present results.
- Faculty I worked under: Diana Krüger, Esteban Lopez Ochoa, Juan Eberhard, Patricio Aroca, Rocio Valdebenito.
- Profile: link.

## Research assistant, Center for Conflict Studies and Social Cohesion

Main tasks: Main programmer of a Regional Labor Market Bulletin. This is a monthly publication that I help to create using RMarkdown and

- Faculty I worked under: Esteban Lopez Ochoa, Patricio Aroca, Juan Eberhard, Nicolas Grau, Monica Navarrete.
- Projects: Labor Market Bulletin; Labor Market App.

#### PAST POSITIONS

#### Research assistant, Business School, Adolfo Ibáñez University

Main tasks: review literature; organize and participate in research meetings and seminars; create R scripts to clean, organize and merge datasets from public sources. Topic: Health Economics.

Faculty I worked under: Florencia Borrescio Higa.

#### Research assistant, Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

- Main tasks: review literature; organize and participate in research meetings and seminars; create R scripts to clean, organize and merge datasets from public sources. Topic: Housing Market.
- Faculty I worked under: Bárbara Navarrete Antinao.

#### RESEARCH

## Working papers

- Title: "When parents skip schools: evidence of suboptimal choices in the Chilean school admission system".
- Document: link.

I Sem. 2020 to date

II Sem. 2021 to date

I Sem. 2020 to date

II Sem. 2017 - II Sem. 2019

I Sem. 2021 - II Sem. 2021

TEACHING

#### Adolfo Ibáñez University

Data Science for Economics and Business

o Course material: <u>link</u>.

TEACHING ASSISTANT

## Adolfo Ibáñez University, graduate level

Spatial Analytics, Ignacio Aravena
Spatial Analytics, Esteban López
II Trim. 2021
I Trim. 2020

## Adolfo Ibáñez University, undergraduate level

Data Science for Economics and Business, Lynn Richards
I Sem. 2021

Microeconomics I, Florencia Borrescio
II Sem. 2017 – I Sem. 2020

II Sem. 2021 to date

Microeconomics II, Diego Avanzini II Sem. 2019
Introduction to Economics, Diego Avanzini I Sem. 2019
Industrial Organization, Diego Avanzini II Sem. 2018

# ADITIONAL INFORMATION

#### Skills

## Software:

- R (*advanced*): Experience with object-oriented programming to developing basic and complex solutions for research-based questions. I have experience with economic modelling programming and developing of web applications (Yo me informo SAE; Labor Market App).
- Stata (intermedium).

## Languages:

German (B1 certificate), English (TOEFL score: 99) and Spanish (native).